<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>Microsoft Teams Platform</title>
	<updated>2025-05-16T04:15:01+05:30</updated>
	<generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
	<subtitle>Updated articles for Microsoft Teams Platform</subtitle>
	<rights>https://learn.microsoft.com/legal/termsofuse</rights>
	<category term="new"/>
	<category term="updated"/>
	<entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Platform update: Introducing Custom Activity Icons in Microsoft Teams]]></title>
		<id>https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12874</id>
		<link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12874?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed"/>
		<updated>2025-05-016T11:04:01+05:30</updated>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing Custom Activity Icons in Microsoft Teams. This is in developer preview. You can now use custom icons for user-triggered notifications in the activity feed in Microsoft Teams.</br></br>Your opinion matters. Drop us your feedback <a href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12874?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed">here</a>!]]></summary>
		<category label="new" term="new"/>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Platform update: Introducing agents usage analytics for third-party apps in Developer Portal]]></title>
		<id>https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12858</id>
		<link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12858?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed"/>
		<updated>2025-05-015T11:04:01+05:30</updated>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[You can now view the Analytics of Microsoft 365 Copilot agent usage for your third-party apps. Explore new Microsoft 365 dimensions in host product and capabilities within Developer Portal for Teams.</br></br>Your opinion matters. Drop us your feedback <a href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12858?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed">here</a>!]]></summary>
		<category label="new" term="new"/>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Platform update: Teams AI library v2 (Developer Preview)]]></title>
		<id>https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12799</id>
		<link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12799?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed"/>
		<updated>2025-05-07T11:04:01+05:30</updated>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing Teams AI library v2. This new library consolidates all the SDKs needed to create collaborative agents for Microsoft Teams.</br></br>Your opinion matters. Drop us your feedback <a href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12799?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed">here</a>!]]></summary>
		<category label="new" term="new"/>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Platform update: Enhance User Experience with Bot Message Streaming]]></title>
		<id>https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12771</id>
		<link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12771?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed"/>
		<updated>2025-05-02T11:04:01+05:30</updated>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are excited to introduce a new feature that will significantly enhance your interaction with our bots. You can now stream bot messages, delivering responses to users as small updates while the complete response is being generated. This improvement aims to enhance the user experience by providing real-time updates.</br></br>Your opinion matters. Drop us your feedback <a href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12771?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed">here</a>!]]></summary>
		<category label="new" term="new"/>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Platform update: Enable OAuth authentication for API based message extension]]></title>
		<id>https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12772</id>
		<link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12772?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed"/>
		<updated>2025-05-02T11:04:01+05:30</updated>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are excited to announce the integration of Open Authorization (OAuth) 2.0 into your Teams API-based message extension app. This integration ensures a secure method for accessing user data from third-party apps without exposing user credentials.</br></br>Your opinion matters. Drop us your feedback <a href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12772?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed">here</a>!]]></summary>
		<category label="new" term="new"/>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Platform update: Precaching apps in Microsoft Teams]]></title>
		<id>https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12630</id>
		<link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12630?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed"/>
		<updated>2025-04-17T11:04:01+05:30</updated>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Say goodbye to slow load times and hello to instant app loading! We're thrilled to announce that you can now precache your app in Microsoft Teams! This exciting update empowers you to opt-in your tab app to be precached in Teams, so that it loads lightning quick from the very first launch! With such blazing fast load times, users spend less time waiting and more time doing what they love.</br></br>Your opinion matters. Drop us your feedback <a href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12630?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed">here</a>!]]></summary>
		<category label="new" term="new"/>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Platform update: Introducing custom engine agents support for Microsoft 365 Copilot Chat]]></title>
		<id>https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12668</id>
		<link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12668?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed"/>
		<updated>2025-04-17T11:04:01+05:30</updated>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're an ISV developer and if you already have a bot on Teams, you can upgrade your existing bots to custom engine agent and add support for custom engine agents in Microsoft 365 Copilot Chat. </br></br>Your opinion matters. Drop us your feedback <a href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12668?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed">here</a>!]]></summary>
		<category label="new" term="new"/>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Platform update: Integrate your apps seamlessly with Public Switched Telephone Network (PSTN) and Teams-to-Teams calls]]></title>
		<id>https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12669</id>
		<link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12669?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed"/>
		<updated>2025-04-17T11:04:01+05:30</updated>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[You can now create personal scope apps that integrate seamlessly with PSTN and Teams-to-Teams calls. By using the right scope and context, you can build apps that effectively utilize tab type, static scope, personal context, and meeting side panels. This integration is super simple and user-friendly. You can either create a new personal tab app or update an existing one with personal scope and the right context. This makes the app more useful and gives users a richer experience during calls. </br></br>Your opinion matters. Drop us your feedback <a href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12669?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed">here</a>!]]></summary>
		<category label="new" term="new"/>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Platform update: App package editor is now available in Developer Portal to manage your app package]]></title>
		<id>https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12605</id>
		<link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12605?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed"/>
		<updated>2025-04-07T11:04:01+05:30</updated>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're an ISV developer, you can create, manage, and customize app packages for Teams. Similar to Visual Studio Code, it enables you to seamlessly edit your app’s components, including the manifest, icons, Copilot agent files, scenes, JSON, and YAML files. You can also add a declarative agent and its related files into your app package. </br></br>Your opinion matters. Drop us your feedback <a href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12605?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed">here</a>!]]></summary>
		<category label="new" term="new"/>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Platform update: Update Bot Endpoint for GCC Compliance]]></title>
		<id>https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12602</id>
		<link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12602?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed"/>
		<updated>2025-03-20T11:04:01+05:30</updated>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[To ensure compliance with GCC (Government Community Cloud) requirements for US-based traffic processing, we’re sharing important guidance on bot endpoint usage.For bot developers, we recommend using the following full qualified domain names for each environment:Public traffic: https://smba.trafficmanager.net/teams/ and GCC traffic: https://smba.infra.gcc.teams.microsoft.com/ </br></br>Your opinion matters. Drop us your feedback <a href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12602?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed">here</a>!]]></summary>
		<category label="new" term="new"/>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Platform update: Introducing New App Installation flow on Microsoft Teams]]></title>
		<id>https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12093</id>
		<link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12093?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed"/>
		<updated>2025-01-16T11:04:01+05:30</updated>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are excited to announce the enhanced user experience for Teams apps installed from Teams Store or via custom upload. With this update, the UI gets more intuitive, user-friendly, straightforward, and easy-to-navigate. Now, adding Teams app in the required scope is just a click away. Key features of this update include the ability to view the available scopes and the scope that gives the best usage experience of that app.</br></br>Your opinion matters. Drop us your feedback <a href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12093?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed">here</a>!]]></summary>
		<category label="new" term="new"/>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Platform update: Introducing 10 BRAND NEW Adaptive Card features in Microsoft Teams]]></title>
		<id>https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12056</id>
		<link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12056?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed"/>
		<updated>2025-01-16T11:04:01+05:30</updated>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[We're thrilled to announce 10 NEW Adaptive Card features now available in Microsoft Teams! These exciting updates empower you to create interactive, dynamic, and visually captivating Adaptive Cards. Supercharge your app development with these powerful new features today. These features are applicable in a wide variety of organizational scenarios - from creating intelligent forms in cards that avoid data entry errors through dependent inputs and conditionally-enabled buttons to visualize business trends through charts.</br></br>Your opinion matters. Drop us your feedback <a href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12056?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed">here</a>!]]></summary>
		<category label="new" term="new"/>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[App validation update: Ensure a secure and user-friendly experience for app users with Nested App Authentication]]></title>
		<id>https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/11548</id>
		<link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/11548?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed"/>
		<updated>2024-10-01T11:04:01+05:30</updated>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Excited to introduce Nested app authentication (NAA) for single-page applications that are embedded in host environment. NAA ensures that users can seamlessly interact with integrated apps within a primary app. It offers all this while maintaining security and enhancing user experience without requiring multiple logins. Use NAA to enable Single Sign-On (SSO) for apps embedded within supported Microsoft apps. NAA improves security by offering better security and flexibility. This allows for the creation of rich, client-driven apps while ensuring a secure and user-friendly experience for app users.</br></br>Your opinion matters. Drop us your feedback <a href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/11548?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed">here</a>!]]></summary>
		<category label="new" term="new"/>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[App validation update: Introduced App analytics for third-party apps in Developer Portal]]></title>
		<id>https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/11610</id>
		<link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/11610?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed"/>
		<updated>2024-10-01T11:04:01+05:30</updated>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're an ISV developer, you now have the capability to access and analyze your app's usage metrics, including monthly, daily, and weekly data, through the Developer Portal. Additionally, you can import your existing or published apps to the Developer Portal to view detailed usage data, such as trends over time, usage by region or country, app usage across different host products and Microsoft 365 (M365) workloads, and the usage of various app capabilities. This enhancement aims to provide full visibility and explore app usage metrics to build better apps and to provide detailed insights into your app performance.</br></br>Your opinion matters. Drop us your feedback <a href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/11610?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed">here</a>!]]></summary>
		<category label="new" term="new"/>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[App validation update: Be proactive in following validation guidelines for your Copilot agent and publish it swiftly!]]></title>
		<id>https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/11611</id>
		<link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/11611?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed"/>
		<updated>2024-10-01T11:04:01+05:30</updated>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’ve introduced comprehensive validation guidelines to help publish your Copilot agents swiftly. By following these guidelines, developers can significantly improve their chances of getting their agents approved and published to the Store faster. Be sure to refer to the updated page for all the details.</br></br>Your opinion matters. Drop us your feedback <a href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/11611?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed">here</a>!]]></summary>
		<category label="new" term="new"/>
	</entry>
</feed>
