<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>Microsoft Teams Platform</title>
	<updated>2025-12-03T04:15:01+05:30</updated>
	<generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
	<subtitle>Updated articles for Microsoft Teams Platform</subtitle>
	<rights>https://learn.microsoft.com/legal/termsofuse</rights>
	<category term="new"/>
	<category term="updated"/>
	<entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Platform update: Copilot AI Insights (meeting recap) API is now generally available]]></title>
		<id>https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/13751</id>
		<link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/13751?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed"/>
		<updated>2025-12-17T11:04:01+05:30</updated>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re thrilled to announce that the Copilot AI Insights (meeting recap) API has officially reached general availability (GA)! This marks a major milestone after an exciting journey through beta, and we’re excited to announce the fully supported v1.0 release to all developers and partners.</br></br>Your opinion matters. Drop us your feedback <a href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/13751?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed">here</a>!]]></summary>
		<category label="new" term="new"/>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Platform update: New capabilities in Microsoft Teams meeting artifacts]]></title>
		<id>https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/13752</id>
		<link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/13752?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed"/>
		<updated>2025-12-17T11:04:01+05:30</updated>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re excited to share that new Graph API capabilities for accessing recordings and transcriptions of adhoc calls have now been released on the Microsoft Teams Platform. These updates, first introduced in beta and now available in v1.0, give you access to recordings and transcripts for Teams VoIP, PSTN, and Graph API–created calls.</br></br>Your opinion matters. Drop us your feedback <a href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/13752?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed">here</a>!]]></summary>
		<category label="new" term="new"/>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Platform update: Microsoft Entra ID auth for bots is now available in group scope!]]></title>
		<id>https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/13637</id>
		<link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/13637?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed"/>
		<updated>2025-05-20T11:04:01+05:30</updated>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’re in a group chat and @mention the bot, you can interact with it without signing in again. The consent card appears only for the user who @mentions the bot for the first time. If the app isn’t pre-installed, user authentication depends on whether Microsoft Entra ID consent is required. In scenarios where consent is needed, the user who @mentions the bot grants permission for the requested access, allowing the bot to acquire an access token and respond within the group chat. When permissions are granted by default or trusted apps, the user can interact with the bot directly without providing consent. Drop us your feedback <a href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/13637?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed">here</a>!]]></summary>
		<category label="new" term="new"/>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Platform update: Introducing Performance Report tool to evaluate web and tab apps efficiency on mobile!]]></title>
		<id>https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/13635</id>
		<link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/13635?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed"/>
		<updated>2025-05-20T11:04:01+05:30</updated>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’re a developer aiming to optimize the performance of your web and tab apps on mobile, the self-serve, lightweight Performance Report tool (Perf tool) is now available. This tool works on Android and iOS, providing real-time performance metrics aligned with industry standards for a superior user experience. It also empowers you to apply Teams-specific best practices directly from your mobile device, making performance evaluation and improvement easier than ever.Drop us your feedback <a href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/13635?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed">here</a>!]]></summary>
		<category label="new" term="new"/>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Platform update: Get Teams meeting insights with Meeting AI Insights]]></title>
		<id>https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12914</id>
		<link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12914?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed"/>
		<updated>2025-05-20T11:04:01+05:30</updated>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[We're thrilled to announce the launch of the Meeting AI Insights API in Microsoft Graph, now available in beta! This powerful API enables you to programmatically access structured AI-generated insights from transcribed Microsoft Teams meetings.</br></br>Your opinion matters. Drop us your feedback <a href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12914?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed">here</a>!]]></summary>
		<category label="new" term="new"/>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Platform update: Introducing Custom Activity Icons in Microsoft Teams]]></title>
		<id>https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12874</id>
		<link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12874?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed"/>
		<updated>2025-05-016T11:04:01+05:30</updated>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing Custom Activity Icons in Microsoft Teams. This is in developer preview. You can now use custom icons for user-triggered notifications in the activity feed in Microsoft Teams.</br></br>Your opinion matters. Drop us your feedback <a href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12874?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed">here</a>!]]></summary>
		<category label="new" term="new"/>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Platform update: Introducing agents usage analytics for third-party apps in Developer Portal]]></title>
		<id>https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12858</id>
		<link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12858?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed"/>
		<updated>2025-05-015T11:04:01+05:30</updated>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[You can now view the Analytics of Microsoft 365 Copilot agent usage for your third-party apps. Explore new Microsoft 365 dimensions in host product and capabilities within Developer Portal for Teams.</br></br>Your opinion matters. Drop us your feedback <a href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12858?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed">here</a>!]]></summary>
		<category label="new" term="new"/>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Platform update: Teams AI library v2 (Developer Preview)]]></title>
		<id>https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12799</id>
		<link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12799?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed"/>
		<updated>2025-05-07T11:04:01+05:30</updated>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing Teams AI library v2. This new library consolidates all the SDKs needed to create collaborative agents for Microsoft Teams.</br></br>Your opinion matters. Drop us your feedback <a href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12799?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed">here</a>!]]></summary>
		<category label="new" term="new"/>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Platform update: Enhance User Experience with Bot Message Streaming]]></title>
		<id>https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12771</id>
		<link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12771?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed"/>
		<updated>2025-05-02T11:04:01+05:30</updated>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are excited to introduce a new feature that will significantly enhance your interaction with our bots. You can now stream bot messages, delivering responses to users as small updates while the complete response is being generated. This improvement aims to enhance the user experience by providing real-time updates.</br></br>Your opinion matters. Drop us your feedback <a href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12771?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed">here</a>!]]></summary>
		<category label="new" term="new"/>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Platform update: Enable OAuth authentication for API based message extension]]></title>
		<id>https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12772</id>
		<link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12772?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed"/>
		<updated>2025-05-02T11:04:01+05:30</updated>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are excited to announce the integration of Open Authorization (OAuth) 2.0 into your Teams API-based message extension app. This integration ensures a secure method for accessing user data from third-party apps without exposing user credentials.</br></br>Your opinion matters. Drop us your feedback <a href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12772?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed">here</a>!]]></summary>
		<category label="new" term="new"/>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Platform update: Precaching apps in Microsoft Teams]]></title>
		<id>https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12630</id>
		<link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12630?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed"/>
		<updated>2025-04-17T11:04:01+05:30</updated>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Say goodbye to slow load times and hello to instant app loading! We're thrilled to announce that you can now precache your app in Microsoft Teams! This exciting update empowers you to opt-in your tab app to be precached in Teams, so that it loads lightning quick from the very first launch! With such blazing fast load times, users spend less time waiting and more time doing what they love.</br></br>Your opinion matters. Drop us your feedback <a href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12630?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed">here</a>!]]></summary>
		<category label="new" term="new"/>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Platform update: Introducing custom engine agents support for Microsoft 365 Copilot Chat]]></title>
		<id>https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12668</id>
		<link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12668?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed"/>
		<updated>2025-04-17T11:04:01+05:30</updated>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're an ISV developer and if you already have a bot on Teams, you can upgrade your existing bots to custom engine agent and add support for custom engine agents in Microsoft 365 Copilot Chat. </br></br>Your opinion matters. Drop us your feedback <a href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12668?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed">here</a>!]]></summary>
		<category label="new" term="new"/>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Platform update: Integrate your apps seamlessly with Public Switched Telephone Network (PSTN) and Teams-to-Teams calls]]></title>
		<id>https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12669</id>
		<link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12669?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed"/>
		<updated>2025-04-17T11:04:01+05:30</updated>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[You can now create personal scope apps that integrate seamlessly with PSTN and Teams-to-Teams calls. By using the right scope and context, you can build apps that effectively utilize tab type, static scope, personal context, and meeting side panels. This integration is super simple and user-friendly. You can either create a new personal tab app or update an existing one with personal scope and the right context. This makes the app more useful and gives users a richer experience during calls. </br></br>Your opinion matters. Drop us your feedback <a href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12669?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed">here</a>!]]></summary>
		<category label="new" term="new"/>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Platform update: App package editor is now available in Developer Portal to manage your app package]]></title>
		<id>https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12605</id>
		<link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12605?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed"/>
		<updated>2025-04-07T11:04:01+05:30</updated>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're an ISV developer, you can create, manage, and customize app packages for Teams. Similar to Visual Studio Code, it enables you to seamlessly edit your app’s components, including the manifest, icons, Copilot agent files, scenes, JSON, and YAML files. You can also add a declarative agent and its related files into your app package. </br></br>Your opinion matters. Drop us your feedback <a href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12605?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed">here</a>!]]></summary>
		<category label="new" term="new"/>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Platform update: Update Bot Endpoint for GCC Compliance]]></title>
		<id>https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12602</id>
		<link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12602?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed"/>
		<updated>2025-03-20T11:04:01+05:30</updated>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[To ensure compliance with GCC (Government Community Cloud) requirements for US-based traffic processing, we’re sharing important guidance on bot endpoint usage.For bot developers, we recommend using the following full qualified domain names for each environment:Public traffic: https://smba.trafficmanager.net/teams/ and GCC traffic: https://smba.infra.gcc.teams.microsoft.com/ </br></br>Your opinion matters. Drop us your feedback <a href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/msteams-docs/discussions/12602?referrer=whats.new.rssfeed">here</a>!]]></summary>
		<category label="new" term="new"/>
	</entry>
	
</feed>
